# OLIVIA POMERANC

#### S O F T W A R E D E V E L O P E R

opomeranc43@gmail.com | +447968756483 | Linkedin: Olivia Pomeranc | Github: OliviaPom

#### ABOUT

I have recently graduated Le Wagon's 9 week intensive coding bootcamp. I made the decision to complete this course due to frustration I experienced whilst completing my physical chemistry master's research.

Though the work was intellectually stimulating and complemented my love for problem solving, I began to desire using this skillset to build tangible products rather than on abstract ideas.

The bootcamp helped me realise my love for constructing clean and functional code, with the additional element of design. I hope to find work as a software engineer in an innovative and friendly company where I am continually pushed to learn and pick up new skills.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Ruby
- Ruby on rails
- CSS / HTML / Bootstrap
- Javascript
- · SQL/ Postgresql
- APIs, JSON, scraping
- · Prototyping, UI design
- Test Driven Development
- · Git, Github, technical workflow
- MVC architecture

#### OTHER INTERESTS

- Electronic music avid listener and learning to DJ!
- Wildlife and conservation I love to travel but with a purpose.
- Running

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Boatface (<u>Link</u>) A rental service web app for luxury yachts with a similar marketplace functionality to Airbnb.
- iGive (<u>Link</u> & Login using: bella@mail.com, password: 123456) A mobile web app, aimed toward young people, allowing them to find the most urgent volunteer opportunities available in their local area.
- · Apps built using the MVC framework in Ruby on Rails.

#### EDUCATION BACKGROUND

# LE WAGON | WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP July - Sept. 2020

- Languages learnt: Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Practical developer skills gained: testing/debugging my code and working collaboratively on Github

#### UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL | CHEMISTRY MSci | FIRST CLASS HONOURS Sept 2016 - June 2020

- Achieved mark of 76 in my master's thesis.
- Through analytical research I became proficient with MATLAB programming language for graphical analysis.
- Spent my third year of university in Singapore, enabling both cultural and academic growth.

#### JFS | SECONDARY SCHOOL

#### Sept. 2008 - June 2015

- GSCE's | achieved 11 A\* grades
- A-LEVELS | **achieved 3 A grades** (Maths, Chemistry, Physics) | also an A grade in Economics AS-Level

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### TEACHING ASSISTANT| LE WAGON Oct 2020 - PRESENT

 Helping students on the web development bootcamp (that I previously completed), to understand concepts and work through challenges confidently.

## RETAIL | &OTHERSTORIES, LEVIS, BURBERRY 2015 - 2018

Keen interest in fashion/art and personable, so enjoyed customer interactions.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# ANIMAL SANTUARY / CONSERVATION 2014, 2016 & 2018

 Volunteered in animal sanctuaries/wildlife conservation in Peru, Madagascar and Bolivia, highlighting my passion for conservation as well as love for travel and new challenges.